Frederick T. Farnsworth Papers MS116
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Frederick T. Farnsworth Papers
1866 -- 1999
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Farnsworth, Frederick Tudor
MS116
3.0 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in five series: Journals and diaries; Notebooks; Letters; Photographs; Drawings.
Biographical / Historical
Frederick T. Farnsworth graduated from Tufts with a bachelor in 1873 and a masters of arts in 1876. He was principal of Sanborn Seminary and taught at the Taunton high-school as well as serving as treasurer of the First Universalist Church in Taunton.
He had two sons, both alumni from Tufts College: Ray D. Farnsworth '09 and Dana T. Farnsworth '06.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of Frederick T. Farnsworth. Farnsworth's journals document his life as a teacher, pricipal, Universalist, and father in New England from 1866 to 1926. His notebooks include his college English class notes and a scrapbook of Medford. The collection also includes letters, photographs, and drawings, the last of which includes building plans in Somerville, MA and New York, NY.
Greater Boston history; Alumni collections
- Journals and diaries, 1866 -- 1926; 1873 -- 1926; MS116.001; 2.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains journals from Frederick T. Farnsworth.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by material type.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Journal no. 1 from West Meridan Connecticut, 1866-01-01 -- 1866-12-26; MS116.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Farnsworth, Frederick T.
  - Journal no. 2 from West Meridan Connecticut, 1866-12-26 -- 1869-08-22; MS116.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Journal no. 3 from Springfield, VT and College, Hill, MA., 1869-08-23 -- 1870-06-04; MS116.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Journal no. 4 from Medford, MA, 1870-06-04 -- 1871-06-22; MS116.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Journal no. 5 from Medford, MA, 1871-06-22 -- 1872-12-21; MS116.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Journal no. 6 from Medford, MA, 1872-12-21 -- 1873-06-30; MS116.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 7 from Somerville, MA and Connecticut., 1873-06-30 -- 1874-08-21; MS116.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 8 from Medford, MA, 1874-08-21 -- 1876-03-13; MS116.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 9 from Medford, MA, 1876-03-13 -- 1877-08-30; MS116.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 10 from Amsterdam, 1877-08-30 -- 1878-08-20; MS116.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 11 from Walpole, MA, 1878-08-20 -- 1880-04-01; MS116.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 12 from Somerville, MA, 1880-04-01 -- 1883-11-08; MS116.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Journal no. 13 from Taunton, MA, 1883-11-08 -- 1888-06-26; MS116.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Journal no. 14 from Taunton, MA, 1888-06-26 -- 1891-07-25; MS116.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Journal no. 15 from Marshfield, MA, 1891-07-25 -- 1893-07-05; MS116.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Journal no. 16 from Medford, MA, 1893-07-05 -- 1894-09-29; MS116.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Journal no. 17 from Williamstown, MA, 1894-09-29 -- 1898-06-10; MS116.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Journal no. 18 from Kingston, NH, 1898-06-10 -- 1901-03-03; MS116.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Journal no. 19 from Kingston, NH, 1901-03-02 -- 1904-06-22; MS116.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Journal no. 20 fromTaunton, MA, 1904-06-22 -- 1906-11-03; MS116.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Journal no. 21 fromTaunton, MA, 1906-11-03 -- 1911-01-08; MS116.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Journal no. 22 fromTaunton, MA, 1911-01-09 -- 1914-02-09; MS116.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Journal no. 23 fromTaunton, MA, 1914-02-09 -- 1916-11-30; MS116.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Journal no. 24, 1916-11-30 -- 1919-07-08; MS116.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Journal no. 25, 1919-07-08 -- 1922-03-09; MS116.001.005.00001 (Box MS116 Shared 1)
  - Journal no. 26 from Taunton, MA, 1922-03-10 -- 1924-09-14; MS116.001.005.00002 (Box MS116 Shared 1)
  - Journal no. 27 from Taunton, MA, 1924-09-14 -- 1926-12-06; MS116.001.005.00003 (Box MS116 Shared 1)
- Notebooks, 1869 -- 1870; 1869 -- 1876; MS116.002; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains notebooks from Frederick T. Farnsworth.
  - College English Journal III, MS116.002.005.00004 (Box MS116 Shared 1)
    This item is undated.
  - Scrapbook, Medford, MA, 1869-08 -- 1870-07; MS116.002.005.00005 (Box MS116 Shared 1)
- Letters, 1909 -- 1963; 1937 -- 1963; MS116.003; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains letters from the Farnsworth family.
  - Misc. Letters, 1953; MS116.003.006.00001 (Box MS116 Shared 2)
    Farnsworth, Dane
  - Wedding Announcement of Candance to Dane Farnsworth Smith, 1937; MS116.003.006.00002 (Box MS116 Shared 2)
  - Dane Farnsworth Smith to Emily Farnsworth, 1909 -- 1963; MS116.003.006.00003 (Box MS116 Shared 2)
    Smith, Dane Farnsworth
- Photographs, 1890 -- 1999; 1899 -- 1999; MS116.004; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains photographs from the Farnsworth family.
  - Photocopies of photographs, 1890 -- 1999; MS116.004.006.00004 (Box MS116 Shared 2)
  - Photographs, misc., 1899 -- 1906; MS116.004.006.00005 (Box MS116 Shared 2)
  - Photographs, misc., 1934; MS116.004.006.00006 (Box MS116 Shared 2)
- Drawings, 1906; MS116.005; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains drawings from the Farnsworth family.
  - Plans for Powderhouse Park, 1906; MS116.005.006.00007; Farnsworth, R.D. (Box MS116 Shared 2)
  - Plans for Double Track Tunnel N.Y.C and H.R.R.R., 1906; MS116.005.006.00008; Farnsworth, R.D. (Box MS116 Shared 2)